Guide to the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), Local 1930 Photographs PHOTOS 017
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), Local 1930 Photographs
1968-1978
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Campbell, Sally C.
AFSCME. Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.)
PHOTOS 017
1 box
Local 1930, New York Public Library Guild, was chartered by the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) in 1968. Members of Local 1930 are employed by the New York Public Library, by the City of New York in its branch libraries, and the libraries of mayoral departments and agencies. The bargaining unit includes professional, non-professional and technical positions. In response to the New York City fiscal crisis of 1975, library support groups made up of library staff and the community at large organized to lobby against an employment freeze, curtailment of services, reduction in weekly hours, branch closings and job terminations. This small collection of 28 (mostly black and white) photographs and four graphics covers the years 1968-1978 and documents some of this resistance; it also includes shots of membership meetings and demonstrations, most of which were used in Local 1930's newsletter.
32 items (5x7, 8x10; b&w and color)
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the New York Public Library Guild, Local 1930 president Sally Campbell in 1979. This donation was established as the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), Local 1930 Records (WAG 040). Photographs from this donation were separated into their own collection, the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), Local 1930 Photographs (PHOTOS 017). The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1979.006 and 2012.050.
Arrangement
Arrangement is chronological.
Files are grouped into one series.
Missing Title
Container List
Historical/Biographical Note
AFSCME Local 1930, better known as the New York Public Library Guild, was chartered by the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) in 1968. Members of Local 1930 are employed by the City of New York in the Branch libraries and the libraries of mayoral departments and agencies and by the New York Public Library. The bargaining unit includes professional, non-professional and technical titles.
In response to the New York City fiscal crisis of 1975, library support groups made up of library staff and the community at large organized to lobby against an employment freeze, curtailment of services, reduction in weekly hours, branch closings and job terminations. In 1978, unions representing city employees negotiated the Coalition Economic Agreement with the City of New York, relating to cost of living adjustment payments. When the New York Public Library refused to comply with the terms of the agreement, contract negotiations came to a standstill and Local 1930 members staged a demonstration before the issue was resolved.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
AFSME, Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.) Records (Wagner 40).
Scope and Content Note
This small collection of 28 (mostly black and white) photographs and four graphics includes shots of membership meetings and demonstrations, most of which were used in the "New York Public Library Guild Local 1930 Newsletter." Of special interest is the photograph from the 1969 demonstration demanding COLA (Cost of Living Adjustment) pay. A cartoon drawing is included - "Public library closed by Governor Carey's veto." Persons pictured include: Local 1930 Presidents Sally Campbell and David Beasley; Local 1930 Secretary, Iris Pettiford Cox; Gay Fruscione, of Local 1321, Queensborough Library Guild; and Belle Weinberg.
Negatives (photographic); Graphic arts; Librarians |z New York (State) |z New York.; Library employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Black-and-white photographs.; Campbell, Sally C.; Weinberg, Belle--Portraits.; Fruscione, Gay; Beasley, David R., 1931- -- |v Portraits; Cox, Iris Pettiford--Portraits.; AFSCME. Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.)
- Container list
  - Membership meeting, Dec 10, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rally to protest curtailment of Research Library hours, May 17, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Tamiment Conference, DC37, Jun 1, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous meetings, 1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Demonstration re 1978-80 contract., Dec 13, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Demonstration re contract negotiations., Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Graphics (including NYPL Research Library lions), Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified negatives., Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Unprocessed Photographs., 1980s, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)